YASH KELKAR

Full Stack Developer

\ +91-8368887424

New Delhi

- @ yashkelkar76@gmail.com
- https://next-portfolio-sand-zeta.vercel.app/
- ☆ https://github.com/theartificialguy



SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with over 2 years of experience in frontend as well as backend software development. Professional hands-on experience in ReactJs, NextJs, React Native, Python, Flask web framework, Firebase, MongoDB, Integrating REST APIs, GIT version control, AI, NLP, OPEN-AI. I have a strong appetite for learning and staying updated with the latest industry trends and best practices.

EXPERIENCE

SDE-1

App-Scoop Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

🗰 2022 - Present 👂 Gurugram, India

- Individually worked on a full-stack react native app with firebase as a robust backend as a service.
- Successfully integrated a dynamic Chat system utilizing Stream SDK for React Native, in addition to implementing a custom payment feature
 with seamless data persistence on Firestore
- Demonstrated adeptness in React, Next, and React Native, implementing industry-best practices such as proficient handling of JS Promises, Async-Await, and employing advanced state-management solutions like Redux, Context-API etc.

SDE Intern

BITCS

苗 2021 - 2021 👂 Gurugram, India

- Worked on production grade mobile application "Changa" (5M+ Downloads) & sportscardinvestor (20K+ Downloads).
- Proficiently utilized cutting-edge technologies including React Native, GIT, and adeptly integrated RESTful APIs, ensuring seamless app performance.
- Employed advanced state-management tools like Redux, Redux Toolkit, Context-API, Zustand etc to maintain state integrity and facilitate optimal app functionality.

PROJECTS

CodeHub

A single place to save your important/go-to code snippets.

- Developed frontend web-app using NextJs with server side rendering.
- Used Firebase firestore as backend along with google cloud functions.
- Integrated Google Authentication to provide integrity and security to the application.
- · Ability to create, save, edit, delete your favourite code snippets along with share feature.

AlgoTurtle

A mobile app that let's people do Algo-Trading in simple steps.

- Frontend developed using React Native, Backend using Python Flask, Firebase as Database.
- · Implemented Subscription Plans using Stripe, React Native & Firebase to store payment, subscription & invoices data.
- Developed payment portal web-app using NextJs with synchronization to update subscription status for a user on both mobile & web-app.

My Portfolio

 ${\boldsymbol{\mathscr{O}}} \ \, \text{https://next-portfolio-sand-zeta.vercel.app}$

Portfolio consisting information about me, my work and my projects.

- Developed using NextJs employing server-side-rendering.
- Consist *some* of my work and *featured* projects, my work experience, education.
- More of my projects can be found in my github: https://github.com/theartificialguy

SKILLS

Javascript	React	Js _	NextJs	Reac	t native	Firebase	MongoDB	Python	Flask	Redux/	Context-API/Zus	tand
Machine Lea	rning	NLP	REST	APIs	NodeJs	ExpressJs	Google C	loud Function	ons G	raphQL	Expo EAS	

EDUCATION

Btech in ECE

GPA

Maharaja Agrasen Institute of Technology, Delhi

= 2017 - 2021

8.44 / 10

PASSION/HOBBY/INTERESTS



Gaming - Esports



Reading Technical blogs



Badminton